<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Maria.engineer -- RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal Website for Maria Mateescu - Software Engineer turned Personal and Professional Coach.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:25:56 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Gaslighter's Guide to Escaping Responsibility]]></title><description><![CDATA[A darkly satirical field guide to emotional manipulation, plausible deniability, and covert abuse.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/gaslighting/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/gaslighting/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nihilistic Eat, Pray, Love]]></title><description><![CDATA[A nihilist's Eat Pray Love: routines, language study, gym crushes, and the messy act of choosing yourself, again and again, even when nothing matters anyway.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/eat-pray-love/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/eat-pray-love/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The worst advice I got as a software engineer]]></title><description><![CDATA[Why 'code wins arguments' became the worst career advice I ever received as a software engineer. How focusing only on technical solutions while ignoring workplace dynamics led to my biggest professional mistake - and what I learned about the human side of engineering.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/worst-advice/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/worst-advice/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Korea: After the Honeymoon]]></title><description><![CDATA[A 6-month retrospective on moving to Seoul, exploring how relationship psychology applies to loving a city after the honeymoon period ends. On choosing problems you can live with, finding equilibrium, and committing to make it work long-term.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/honeymoon/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/honeymoon/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Learning to be Enough]]></title><description><![CDATA[I was the gifted child who was never enough. This is the story of my journey of learning how to be enough.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/enough/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/enough/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[When Crush Turns to Like]]></title><description><![CDATA[What's the difference between a crush and actually liking someone? When we actually like someone we may need to change what we to do about it. But while the solution is simple, it's not easy.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/gym-like/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/gym-like/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[An Alternative to Journaling: Writing Fiction]]></title><description><![CDATA[I have always struggled with journaling, yet every therapist has recommended it. I realised fiction writing was my form of journaling - a freedom to express myself that I could not through traditional journaling. Just because it's fictional, doesn't make it any less true.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/fictional-journaling/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/fictional-journaling/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building Emotional Intelligence and Healing Through Fiction]]></title><description><![CDATA[Discover how fiction builds emotional intelligence better than self-help books. Learn why K-dramas, novels, and stories teach empathy and emotional healing through the 'show don't tell' approach that transforms how we understand ourselves and others.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/fiction/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/fiction/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Happiness isn't the goal, it's the metric]]></title><description><![CDATA[Chasing happiness makes it impossible to find it. After trying to find meaning and failing, I learned that happiness works better as a metric than a goal. Only then we can allow the meaningless things to make us happy.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/happiness/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/happiness/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Am I Overreacting?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stop asking 'Am I overreacting?' Learn why your emotional responses are valid, how to trust your intuition, and break free from self-doubt. Includes solo travel safety tips and coaching resources.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/overreacting/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/overreacting/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[What would you forget?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Explore the fascinating concept of selective memory erasure and its implications. Drawing from neuroscience, trauma research, and personal reflection, this article examines how memory works, why some memories cause suffering, and offers a transformative alternative to forgetting painful experiences.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/mind-laundry/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/mind-laundry/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Coaching Tool: Waiting Room]]></title><description><![CDATA[Discover the 'Waiting Room' coaching tool for managing tasks outside your control and reducing anxiety. Learn how to visualize a mental waiting room for pending tasks, when to use it, and why this simple technique helps maintain focus on what truly matters right now.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/waiting-room/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/waiting-room/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Don't Get Me Wrong]]></title><description><![CDATA[Being misunderstood is one of my greatest fears. In this post, I explore three types of misunderstanding: from the curious kind when people genuinely want to learn, to the willful kind when people choose not to understand. I share my personal journey of making peace with inevitable misinterpretations, and how coaching others taught me that sometimes, misunderstandings reveal more about what truly matters to the listener.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/misunderstood/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/misunderstood/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[I don’t want to be perceived]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today of all days, the last thing I want to do is be perceived, yet I am writing this blog post, as a challenge to myself as to what it means to be perceived, and that it's not as unsafe as it feels.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/no-perception/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/no-perception/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Importance of Being Seen]]></title><description><![CDATA[Being seen is one of the most powerful human needs and one of the most overlooked. In the age of smartphones even more so. I look back at the times when people saw me and just how much they affected me.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/seen/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/seen/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[We All Need a Little External Validation]]></title><description><![CDATA[External validation isn’t just okay—it’s essential for human connection and societal functioning. Instead we should learn when it’s healthy, when it’s harmful, and how to find our balance.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/external_validation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/external_validation/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[I Learned Not to Trust Perfection]]></title><description><![CDATA[A personal reflection on the dangers of perfectionism. How it appears in and distorts love, faith, and self-worth. This post explores the myth of perfection through the lens of religion, relationships, and identity, and looks at how I am learning to let go of it.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/perfection/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/perfection/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[AI: A Prediction]]></title><description><![CDATA[An exploration of AI's current trajectory, the over-reliance on LLMs, the risks of AI-generated code, and why human engineers will remain indispensable. And why I am preparing my popcorn for the next Hindenburg moment.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/ai-predictions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/ai-predictions/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Do Not Come Here For Justice]]></title><description><![CDATA[They say staying is a choice. But staying in a toxic relationship isn't the real choice we make. It’s the pursuit of justice. We believe fairness can be achieved if we just try hard enough, but that belief often keeps us trapped. When justice fails as a survival strategy, what’s left? Letting go can be the hardest but most necessary lesson.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/justice/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/justice/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Just because I can doesn't mean I should]]></title><description><![CDATA[This Valentine's Day, I reflect on the biggest lesson my past relationship taught me: just because I can, doesn’t mean I should. Independence is great, and it's necessary to create a healthy interdependent relationship. But that doesn't mean doing it all.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/just-because-i-can/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/just-because-i-can/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Onboarding: what makes or breaks a team]]></title><description><![CDATA[Effective onboarding shapes a team’s success. Here’s how to do it right (and what happens when you don’t).]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/onboarding/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/onboarding/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Korea - observations on culture]]></title><description><![CDATA[Why move to Korea? From cultural values to personal growth, I reflect on how Korea rekindled my ambition and why this country feels like home.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/why_korea/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/why_korea/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Most Under-utilised Gym Motivation Tool: the Gym Crush]]></title><description><![CDATA[Gym Crushes are well too common, and they make our day better just to see them in the same space as us. Enjoy them as you get ripped for chances are they won't last, unlike the habits they help form.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/gym_crush/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/gym_crush/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Starter Villain: A People Pleaser's Guide to Villainy]]></title><description><![CDATA[This one is for the people pleasers: let us be villains! An exploration of the start of my villain era, 2024, and the lessons I learned.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/starter_villain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/starter_villain/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[On Urgency: A Reframe]]></title><description><![CDATA[A rephrase of urgency not just as about deadlines, but as impact. Explore a reframe of the Eisenhower Matrix and learn how cognitive reframing can help you prioritise tasks effectively while avoiding burnout.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/urgency/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/urgency/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[On Decisions and Change]]></title><description><![CDATA[Decisions are hard, but change doesn't have to be scary. Explore how embracing flexibility, managing uncertainty, and practicing self-compassion can lead to better choices and personal growth.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/decisions/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/decisions/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Relaxation and Mindfulness: When One Size Does Not Fit All]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello from Bali! The ultimate vacation destination, the epitome of relaxation, the mindfulness Mecca... for most people. ]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/relaxation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/relaxation/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Listen with Curiosity]]></title><description><![CDATA[Lead with curiosity in conversations: How focusing on differences, overcoming assumptions, and embracing the unknown are keys to empathetic communication and effective problem-solving.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/curiosity/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/curiosity/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Coaching: Anchors Only Bring Safety in a Storm]]></title><description><![CDATA[Clinging onto anchors(such as jobs, relationships or commitments that don't serve our deeper desires) can prevent one from moving forward. Security necessary in a turmoil can become a hinderance when freedom calls.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/anchors/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/anchors/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stuck on Forwards Compatibility]]></title><description><![CDATA[A post exploring the parallels between forward compatibility in software engineering and personal growth. Discover how obsessing over planning for the future can hinder real-life progress and how to embrace change more effectively.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/forwards_compatibility/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/forwards_compatibility/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Korean: -ㄹ 거예요 vs -ㄹ께요]]></title><description><![CDATA[Musings about the Korean language, as a new language learner. The future tenses -ㄹ 거예요 vs -ㄹ께요.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/korean_future_tenses/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/korean_future_tenses/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Things Between Heaven And Earth]]></title><description><![CDATA[5★ - Things Between Heaven and Earth, a thought-provoking psychological thriller at the Camden Fringe that brilliantly explores complex human relationships and attachment with authenticity and depth.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/theatre/heaven_and_earth/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/theatre/heaven_and_earth/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Coaching: You Can't Learn Regular Expressions from Only Positive Examples]]></title><description><![CDATA[We need to make mistakes in order to learn, just like we need negative examples to train models in Computer Science. Why creating a safe environment for mistakes is crucial for genuine learning and development.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/positive_examples/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/positive_examples/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Code with Push Safety in Mind]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to code with push safety in mind. This comprehensive guide covers backwards and forwards compatibility, common pitfalls in database changes and frontend updates, and best practices for seamless software deployments.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/push_safety/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/push_safety/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Software Engineers are Disambiguators]]></title><description><![CDATA[Explore the evolving role of software engineers as disambiguators, from the history of programming languages to speculations on AI's impact on the field and why I think coding is the least essential part of a software engineer's job.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/disambiguation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/disambiguation/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chicken Crisps]]></title><description><![CDATA[Healthy snack that tastes sinful.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/chicken_crisps/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/chicken_crisps/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Withstanding Pressure: Lessons of a Recovering People Pleaser]]></title><description><![CDATA[As a recovering people pleaser 2024 is the start of my villain era. Here are some mantras and techniques I vow to start and continue using in order to enable myself to withstand pressure and set boundaries.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/withstanding_pressure/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/withstanding_pressure/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Blog Posts: a Meta Post on Writing Posts]]></title><description><![CDATA[Facing writer’s block? This post tackles common mental biases that can make it hard to identify valuable blog topics and believe others will benefit. Learn how to combat sampling, undercoverage, and egocentric biases.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/blog_posts/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/blog_posts/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[When Obvious Isn't Obvious: The Pantomime Trap]]></title><description><![CDATA[Do childhood pantomimes develop communication skills? Can they encourage perspective-taking and clear communication free of assumptions?]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/pantomime_trap/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/pantomime_trap/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ode to Monorepos]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my ode to monorepos, and how they simplify refactors, prevent duplicate work, and foster open culture.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/monorepos/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/monorepos/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Macro-ifying Microservices: A Way to Think about Microservices]]></title><description><![CDATA[Microservices have gone from architectural pattern to default for many. But micro doesn't have to mean small. Macro-ifying microservices based on problem spaces simplifies software design.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/microservices/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/microservices/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Mirror]]></title><description><![CDATA[5★ - Five stars and more, this play is perfection from beginning to end. Poignant in an era where our right of protest is slowly being taken away. While it looks like the censorship in communist regimes, it proves it can be anywhere.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/theatre/a_mirror/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/theatre/a_mirror/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beetroot Bors]]></title><description><![CDATA[Refreshing cold sour soup]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/bors/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/bors/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Classic Tiramisu]]></title><description><![CDATA[A variation on the Italian dessert.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/tiramisu/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/tiramisu/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Salty Birb]]></title><description><![CDATA[A tequila and pineapple cocktail.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/salty_birb/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/salty_birb/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cauliflower Cheese]]></title><description><![CDATA[A simpler cauliflower souffle.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/cauliflower_cheese/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/cauliflower_cheese/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Experience Getting Fired]]></title><description><![CDATA[December 2021, I got fired from my job. It took me a long time to process what happened, maybe I never fully did, but here are some of my learnings.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/fired/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/fired/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oklahoma!]]></title><description><![CDATA[4★ - A modern take on the popular Rodgers and Hammerstein classic, Oklahoma! pulls out all the stops to try and give life to a musical that honestly hasn't aged well.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/theatre/oklahoma/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/theatre/oklahoma/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Secret Life of Bees]]></title><description><![CDATA[5★ - This is a new musical by Duncan Sheik, known for his work on Spring Awakening. Although I had high expectations, I was surprised by how good it turned out to be. The musical is consistently great, and I predict that it will become very popular.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/theatre/secret_life_of_bees/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/theatre/secret_life_of_bees/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Good Person of Szechwan]]></title><description><![CDATA[3.5★ - Overall, it was an enjoyable experience. I would describe it as loud and chaotic, yet entertaining and fresh. Considering they took a highly intellectual play by Brecht that some may consider dry, and turned it into something fun and probably enjoyable for the masses, while also not losing the message of the play, is impressive in its own right.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/theatre/good_person_szechwan/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/theatre/good_person_szechwan/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Operation Mincemeat]]></title><description><![CDATA[4★ - This is a really good show - incredibly fun and fresh. Did I mention hilarious? I can't bring myself to go for a full 5 star rating as it was missing something from being great. For example scientific accuracy... A newt does not have an anus.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/theatre/operation_mincemeat/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/theatre/operation_mincemeat/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[George Takei's Allegiance]]></title><description><![CDATA[5★ - This musical was nothing short of brilliant. The only thing I could possibly find bad about it is that they did not sell out. I don't really understand how that could happen.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/theatre/allegiance/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/theatre/allegiance/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lemons Lemons Lemons Lemons]]></title><description><![CDATA[2★ - While the premise, in itself, is brilliant, and the topics brought up are interesting and worth presenting in a play, the play under-delivers on all fronts. I cannot call it anything other than a disappointment.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/theatre/Lemons_lemons_lemons/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/theatre/Lemons_lemons_lemons/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Steps of Buying a House in the UK]]></title><description><![CDATA[Buying a house has been an overwhelming experience. As such I built a list of all the things I had to do and consider, if others may want to use it.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/house_purchase/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/house_purchase/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Find a House to Buy a House in the UK]]></title><description><![CDATA[A record of all the steps I went through to find the house I currently own.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/finding_a_house/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/finding_a_house/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Choose a Survey Type]]></title><description><![CDATA[This is my guide on how I chose a Survey for a house purchase. One of the more confusing decisions when buying a house was what kind of survey to get. Some surveyors had complicated names, each offering different packages none entirely clear about which you should get and why.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/survey-house-purchase/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/survey-house-purchase/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Ways to Improve your Work Life Balance]]></title><description><![CDATA[Working longer doesn't mean working better. Many go on about Work Life balance, but many companies have policies that go against it. Here's my top tips on practical things I do to improve my work life balance.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/work_life_balance_tips/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/work_life_balance_tips/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grandma's Walnut Cake]]></title><description><![CDATA[A simple recipe for a nutty loaf cake.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/walnut_cake/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/walnut_cake/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grandma's Zacusca]]></title><description><![CDATA[Traditional Romanian pepper tapenade]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/zacusca/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/zacusca/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Reasons you Should Build UIs Instead of CLIs]]></title><description><![CDATA[While the "Real Programmer" will always choose to use CLIs as they are the true sign of competence, good UIs with good defaults are actually the better choice when building tools of the average software engineer.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/blog/uis_over_clis/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/blog/uis_over_clis/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grandma's Krafle]]></title><description><![CDATA[Doughnuts made from cozonac dough]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/krafle/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/krafle/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Roasting Peppers]]></title><description><![CDATA[Essential pepper preparation method]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/roasted_peppers/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/roasted_peppers/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Grandma's Stuffed Peppers]]></title><description><![CDATA[Peppers with pork and rice stuffing.]]></description><link>https://maria.engineer/food/stuffed_peppers/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://maria.engineer/food/stuffed_peppers/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>